#Encodergasm Presents
～
This strange story began on a blistering hot day.
（ジェット）
この奇妙な事件の始まりは
うだるような暑い日だった
I had received an unexpected mail from an old acquaintance of mine...
古い知り合いから 突然のメールが
舞い込んできたんだが―
...but the message was just this:
その文面は
たった これだけだった
"Seek the sacred beast from Anzan."
“案山より聖獣を見いだせ”
"I am at the meeting place of the four gods."
“我 四神相応に有り”
Pao, the sender of the message, was an acquaintance of mine...
（ジェット）差出人のパオは
知り合いとはいえ
...but it didn't mean that we kept in touch all that well.
それほどの
付き合いだったわけじゃない
I grew suspicious, and started to research Pao's current whereabouts.
不審に思った俺は
パオの行方を調べることにした
パオは この火星で―
They say that Pao is one of the three greatest Feng Shui masters here on Mars.
３本の指に入るほどの
風水師だというが―
俺が行方を突き止めたとき
やつは既に この世にいなかった
But when I found his whereabouts, he had already left this world.
Are you sure you weren't the one that sent me this mail?
お前さんが
メールをくれたんじゃないのか？
The one who visits from the inauspicious back door...
（メイファ）
“裏鬼門より訪ね来る者”
...receive the word from the heavens, and lead me to the sun stone.
“天の声を受け
なんじを太陽石に導かん”
Just like what the pa-kua told me!
はっけの託宣どおり！
ああん？
Look out!
危ない！
どこ 撃ってる？
Where are you shooting?!
They sure are disrespectful fellows.
罰当たりな連中だな
The escape route!
活路へ！
Hey?
おい
Hey, hey!
おおい おい
Idiot!
（ギャングＡ）ぼけ！
（ギャングＢ）くそ
Shit!
Hey, hey, hey!
おおい！ おい おい
（車のクラクション）
Escape route!
活路！
Chi of Earth!
地の気
（ジェット）おおい！
ぷはあ
（荒い息）
That was really close!
危機一髪ってやつですね
I'm glad you're safe.
よかった　助かって
へえっくし！
（スパイク）何やってんだ？
What are you doing?
（フェイ）ちょっと ちょっと
あれ 誰？
Hey, over there...  Who is that?
（スパイク）うん？
ほーお
I wonder if she's a new girlfriend.
新しい恋人かな？
随分 若い彼女だな
For that, she's rather young.
Weird one, hot dog bun, loved one!
（エド）
変人 ニンジン 愛人～
Maybe she's his secret love-child?
隠し子とか？
随分 年食った娘だな
For that, she's rather old.
Child, mild, wild!
（エド）
チャイルド マイルド ワイルドー
But I'm surprised.
（ジェット）しかし 驚いたよ
I wasn't expecting Pao's daughter to be this old already.
パオの娘さんが
こんなに大きくなってるなんてな
You probably don't remember...
（ジェット）
あんたは覚えてないだろうが―
...but I met you once when you were this little.
まだ こんな小さかった頃
会ったことがあるんだぜ
How do you know my father?
父とは どういう
お知り合いなんですか？
How?
どうって…
Just an acquaintance.  It's been 10 years already.
ただの知り合いさ
もう10年も前だ
しかし おやじさんも
交通事故とは運がねえ
But your father sure was unlucky to be in a traffic accident...
On the way to Jupiter, there was a sudden spatial fluctuation in hyperspace.
木星へ向かう途中―
位相差空間の中で
突然 時空のゆがみが起きて…
にゃー
Here you go.
どうぞ
Thank you.
ありがと
Are you the "girlfriend?"
愛人ですか？
Are you the "secret love-child?"
隠し子ですかー？
Rejected!
ぎょーくさーい
Mr.  Jet, why were you at the graveyard?
ジェットさん どうして墓地に？
父が事故に遭ったことは
身内以外は誰も…
Nobody outside the family knows he got into an accident...
"Seek the sacred beast from Anzan."
“案山より聖獣を見いだせ”
“我 四神相応に有り”
"I am at the meeting place of the four gods."
This is?
これは？
Pao sent me this.
パオから俺の所に送られてきた
When?
（メイファ）いつですか？
Three days ago.
３日前だ
Right before the accident...
（メイファ）事件の直前…
Please!  Can you help me?!
お願いです
私に協力してください
I'm sure this is the whereabouts of the sun stone!
（メイファ）これは きっと
太陽石の在りかです
Sun stone?
太陽石？
The direction, day, and time you arrived was the best combination for Feng Shui!
あなたの現れた方角 月日 時間は
風水的には最も良いのです
特に探し物をするときには！
Especially when you're searching for something!
そうなのか？
I-It was?
It was!
そうなんです
お願い！ ジェットさん
Please, Mr.  Jet!
Yes.  About that, we will have it soon.
（ギャングＢ）
はい！ そらもう すぐに！
Yes, I understand.
はい！ 分かりました
How was the boss feeling?
ボスの機嫌は？
Well...
それが…
いいわけねえか
There's no way it could be good.
Of course not...
そりゃ もう
Let's go!
行くぞ
I didn't have any particular favors to repay to Pao or this girl...
（ジェット）
パオにも この娘にも 特に
恩義があるわけじゃなかったが
...but I decided to help them for now.
とりあえず
俺は協力することにした
There were too many things that made me suspicious to leave it alone.
放っておくには
気に掛かることが多すぎたからだ
Why did Pao send me mail right before his death?
パオは なぜ死ぬ前に
俺にメールを送ってきたのか？
What do those words mean?
あの言葉は どういう意味なのか？
Who were those guys that attacked us?
襲ってきた連中は何者なのか？
And there was something about this girl named Meifa as well...
それに このメイファという娘も
気になるところがあった
この宇宙は
三つの気から できています
This universe is made of three different Chis.
それは天の気
One is the Chi of Heaven, the energy that comes from the Sun.
すなわち 太陽から
やってくるエネルギーと―
地の気
One is the Chi of Earth, the energy that comes from a planet's surface.
すなわち その惑星の大地から
湧き上がってくるエネルギー
And lastly Chi of Magnetism, the Chi that organisms like ourselves produce.
そして磁気
すなわち 私たち生物自体から
出ている気なんです
生物の気？
Chi from organisms?
人間の体には
常に磁場が生じているんです
The human body always produces a magnetic field.
その磁場と地球の磁場とは―
That magnetic field and the magnetic field of the Earth...
お互いに反応し合って
作用しています
...react to one another to create energy.
そういった大自然のエネルギーを
読み取り―
Universal Feng Shui is the technology that reads the energies...
活用していく技術が
宇宙風水なんです
...of nature such as this to use them in everyday life.
アイス
Ice cream.
Universal Feng Shui...
宇宙風水
占いみたいなもんとは違うのか？
It's not the same thing as fortunetelling?
他の占術は せいぜい
予測や予知をするだけです
Other fortunetelling methods only predict or prognosticate.
でも宇宙風水は―
However, Universal Feng Shui has the power to make the bad into the good.
凶を吉に変える力を
持ってるんですよ
例えば 父ぐらいの力を持つ
風水師になると…
For example, if you were a Feng Shui master as powerful as my father...
んんー どうした？
What's wrong?
父とは こんなふうに
過ごしたこと なかったなと思って
I just realized that I never spent time like this with my father.
おいおい 言っとくが
俺は そんな年じゃねえぞ
Hey, now.
Let me point out that I'm not that old.
If anything, I would be a boyfriend...
どっちかっていうと恋人…
いやあ 恋人は まずいだろ
No, wait, that would be bad.
なっ ううー
何 言ってんだ？ 俺は
W-What am I saying?
せめて お兄さんとか何とか
At least I can be an elder brother or something...
Ice cream...
アイス
（ジェット）えっ？
Ice cream.
ウフ　行きましょ ジェットさん
Let's go, Mr.  Jet!
（メイファ）案山とは恐らく ここ
I believe that "Anzan" refers to here.
The Mountain Hotel Building...
マウンテンホテルビルのこと
あれです！
There!
青龍
Seiryu!
"Blue Dragon"
白虎
Byakko!
"White Tiger"
玄武
Genbu!
"Black Turtle"
Suzaku!
"Scarlet Phoenix"
朱雀
おおい…
Hey...
I know, the cross-zenith method!
そうか！ 十字天心の法
太陽石は ここに
The sun stone is here!
本当かよ？
Are you sure?
いたいた いましたぜ
There they are.  They're right over there.
All right.
ようし
おっと
ついに見つけた
I finally found it.
これが太陽石ね
This must be the sun stone.
こんなのが？
This thing?
あっ ジェットさん？
Mr.  Jet?
（子供たち）ああっ
（ギャングＢ）どいてろ
（子供Ａ）ああ
Outta the way.
What are you doing?
（子供Ａ）何すんだよ！
ラオチュウ １本
グラスは いらねえ
One bottle of lao-chu.  I don't need a glass.
えいっ こらっ このー
Take that!
Hey, who are you guys?
おい お前ら 何もんだ？
へっ そう簡単に
げろすると思ってんのかよ
Heh, you think we would tell you that easily...
わあ くっ くっ うっ
ブルースネークのもんですう
W-We're from the Blue Snake.
やっぱり 組織のもんか
So you ARE from a syndicate.
なんで俺たちをつけ回す？
Why are you following us around?
そ それだけは
たとえ殺されても言えねえなあ
I-I couldn't tell you that even if you killed me.
ぐうううっ
パオのやつをやり損ねたんで―
I-It was because we couldn't get Pao...
...so they told us to get the recipient of his mail.
あいつからのメールの受取人を
捕まえろって…
ぐあああ
I-I'm telling the truth!
ほ 本当です
僕たち下っ端なんで
それ以上 知りませーん
We're on the low end so we don't know any more than that!
I'm sure.
そうだろうな
（メイファ）ジェットさん
Mr.  Jet...
父が―
My father... is alive?
生きてる？
（ジェット）パオの言葉は
この石の在りかを示していた
Pao's words showed where this stone was.
パオは やはり
どこかで生きているのか？
Does that mean Pao is still alive somewhere?
この石を捜し出して
俺に何をさせたかったのか？
Did he want me to find this stone and do something with it?
謎は解けるどころか ますます
深まっちまったように感じる
It feels like I created more mysteries instead of solving them.
とりあえず俺は―
For now, I decided to check out this stone, which was our only clue.
唯一の手がかりの この石を
調べてみることにした
50年前のゲート事故のときの
月のかけらか
So this is a piece of the moon from that Gate accident 50 years ago.
私たち風水師の間では
太陽石と呼ばれています
We Feng Shui masters call it the sun stone.
時空のゆがみを吸収して―
It's absorbed the fluctuations in time and space...
とてつもないエネルギーを
秘めているんです
...and conceals a tremendous amount of energy.
あうう
I can only think of it as a plain old rock.
ただの石っころにしか
見えねえけどなあ
So, how much would it be if we sold it?
で？ 売れば
どれぐらいになるわけ？
Hey, guys, if you're gonna smoke, go smoke outside.
（ジェット）おい お前ら
たばこ 吸うなら 外で吸ってこい
What?
なあに？ 自分だって
いつも吸ってんじゃない
You always smoke in here, too!
I'm turning this into a non-smoking area starting today.
（ジェット）
今日から ここは禁煙にする
おいおい 冗談だろ？
Hey, now, you're kidding, right?
この船は俺の船だ　知ってたか？
This ship is MY ship, remember?
（エド）うーん？ んー？
（ジェット）
で この石をどうするってんだ？
So, what are you gonna do with this stone?
（メイファ）
それが分からないんです
I... have no idea.
一体 父が
どういうつもりなのか…
I don't know what my father is thinking...
Oh, hey, wait!
おいおい こら アイン 待て
Ein!  Wait!
（エド）にゃー？
The luo-pan...
羅盤が！
What?
何だ？
That can't be.  I took the magnet off.
そんな！ 磁石を外してあるのに
そうか
I see...  I get it now.
そうだわ
（ジェット）ううん？
そうなのね
So that's it!
にゃにゃ？
THAT'S IT!!
そうなんだわ！
（メイファ）確か父も
太陽石を持っていたはずです
If I remember correctly, my father owned a sun stone as well.
I'm sure that the two stones are resonating...
きっと これは
石同士が引き合って―
...to show me the whereabouts of my father.
父のいる場所を
示しているんだと思います
And that's why Pao made you look for this stone...
（ジェット）それでパオは
この石を捜させたってわけか
But...
でも―
I don't know why my father sent the mail to you, Mr.  Jet...
父は なぜジェットさんに
メールを送ったのかしら
...and not to me...
私… じゃなく…
にゃにゃにゃにゃー
どう思う？
What do you think?
（スパイク）
いいコンビじゃねえの？
They make a good couple.
ああいうタイプは危ないんだよね
It's a dangerous combination.
（スパイク）何が？
What is?
The more righteous a guy was in his youth...
若い頃
真面目だった男のほうが―
年いってから若い子に
入れ込んじゃったりするもんなのよ
...the more likely he's gonna fall for a young girl later in life.
（スパイク）やっぱり？
Is that so?
男も理屈じゃないわ 実際
Really...  Guys are so clueless.
（メイファ）
父は宇宙風水だけを信じて
人を信じない
My father...
...was one that believed in Universal Feng Shui, but not other people...
そんな人だった
だから母は
私を連れて家を出たんです
...so my mother left the house, and took me along.
７年前に
That was seven years ago...
父なら 私たちが どこにいるか
すぐに見つけられたはずなのに―
I'm sure my father was able to find our whereabouts easily.
父は捜してもくれなかった
But he never even tried to look for us...
きっと事情があったのさ
I'm sure there was a reason behind it.
父は なぜ
あの人たちに狙われたんですか？
Why was my father targeted by those men?
悪い人たちの仲間だったから？
Was it because he was friends with bad people?
Please, tell me the truth!
お願いです
本当のことを教えてください
Who my father really was...
父の本当の姿を
Pao... was the consultant for a syndicate.
（ジェット）パオは―
組織のコンサルタントをしてた
それは事実だ
That's the truth.
Pao had leaked information to me about...
パオは刑事だった俺に
組織の情報を流してくれてた
...the syndicate, back when I was a detective.
その頃 既にパオは
組織から抜けたがってた
Pao already wanted out of the syndicate back then.
だが 組織の重要な秘密を
知ってる人間が―
However, it's impossible for someone who knows...
...important syndicate secrets to ever leave the group.
そこを抜けるなんてことは不可能だ
パオはきっと―
I'm sure Pao was afraid that more bad things would happen to his family.
家族に余計な災難が
降りかかるのを恐れたんだろう
ま 本人に会ったら
自分で確かめるといいさ
Well, I'm sure you can confirm it all when you see him.
にゃーにゃーにゃー
（メイファ）
ここです！ この辺りに
Here!
Around here...
There isn't anything here.
（フェイ）何もないわよ
レーダーは？
How about the radar?
No response.
（スパイク）反応なし
That can't be.  I'm sure this is the place.
（メイファ）そんな！
確かに この場所のはずなのに
（スパイク）うん？ いや
Hmm?  Wait...
（スパイク）待った
Hold on...
（メイファ）わっ
Do we have guests?
お客さんか？
しつこい連中だぜ
They sure are persistent.
スパイク！ フェイ！ 頼む
Spike, Faye, please take care of them!
あんたのお客じゃないの？
Aren't they YOUR guests?
この船と心中したくなきゃ
協力するこった
Help me out if you don't wanna die with this ship!
とんだ貧乏くじだわ
What rotten luck of the draw.
（スパイク）
たまには損得抜きもいいさ
Sometimes it's good to act without asking "What's in it for me?".
王女の夢をかなえる
妖精さんってわけだ
We're fairies who are going to grant the princess' wish.
We are?
（フェイ）あんたが？
無人機か
Unmanned fighters?
さしずめ７人の小人ってとこか
So these would be the seven dwarves...
（メイファ）あっ ああ…
Shit!  They're trying to scare us!
くそお　落としてやる
（エド）分かったよー
I got it!
（ジェット）スパイク 戻ってくれ
Spike!  Come back here!
What?!
何だ？
Apparently, if we apply lots of energy to that stone...
（ジェット）例の石に
高いエネルギーをかけると
...we can draw out all the forces trapped inside it.
中に封じ込められた力を
引き出せるらしい
And, what are we going to do?
で どうすりゃいいんだ？
いちかばちかの作戦だが…
This is an all-or-nothing plan, but...
何でもいいから早くしてよ
I don't care what it is, just hurry!
I put it in!
入れたよー
（ジェット）ようし
All right!
プラズマカノンで
この石をぶち抜いてくれ！
Blast this rock with your plasma cannon.
大した作戦だぜ
What a great plan this is...
（ジェット）うん？
Looks like you made it in time, Jet.
（パオ）間に合ったな ジェット
パオ！ お前…
Pao!  You're...
Meifa...  It's been a while.
メイファ 久しぶりだ
Pao, you're in unstable territory.  I can't approach any closer than this.
パオ そっちは不安定領域だ
これ以上は近づけん
I know...  There isn't any oxygen left in here anyway.
分かっている
どのみち酸素が もうない
I sent you that mail because I wanted you to bring my daughter here...
（パオ）
お前さんにメールを送ったのは
ここに娘を
連れてきてほしかったからだ
Then... you willed us to be here like this using Feng Shui?!
（ジェット）じゃあ こうして
俺たちが現れることは―
お前の風水の見立てだってのか？
Yeah...
（パオ）そうだ
違うぜ パオ
お前が仕組んだわけじゃない
That's not true, Pao.
This wasn't your doing.
Meifa is here now...
メイファが ここにいるのは―
...because she WANTED to come here.
彼女自身が
ここに来たかったからさ
フッ…　そうかもしれん
You might be right.
わしは思い上がっていたのかもな
Perhaps I was being too hotheaded.
メイファ
Meifa, it's wonderful to see you one last time.
最後にお前に会えてよかったよ
I hated you all this time...
（メイファ）ずっと―
あなたのこと 恨んでたわ
I despised you all this time...
ずっと あなたが憎かった
それなのに…
But...
Papa...
Now, I don't know if it was a good thing or a bad thing that we took her along.
（ジェット）
彼女を連れていったことが
よかったのか悪かったのか
今となっては分からない
In any case, this was how this strange case ended.
とにかく こうして
この奇妙な事件は終わり―
She went back to Mars.
彼女は火星へ帰っていった
And the smoking ban was lifted from the living quarters.
そして
リビングの禁煙も解除され―
Once again, unchanging daily life has returned, just as it was before.
いつもどおりの
何も変わらない日々が戻ってきた
One thing that has changed, though...
一つだけ変わったことといえば―
I no longer read the fortunetelling pages in magazines.
雑誌の占いのページを
読まなくなったことぐらいだ
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
He... came with a whistle.
（ジェット）やつは
と共にやって来た
A man, Andy, made a sudden appearance on horseback.
（ジェット）
突如 馬に乗って現れた男
アンディ
Who in the world is he?
彼は一体 何者か？
敵か？ 味方か？
Is he an ally or a foe?  Or is he a true cowboy?
それとも本物のカウボーイなのか？
The next episode is a shocking sci-fi macaroni-western epic saga: Cowboy Funk.
次回 衝撃のＳＦマカロニ巨編
「カウボーイ･ファンク」
Wait a minute, isn't this world view a bit different?
ちょっと
世界観 違うんじゃねえか？